TAUFIK HIDAYAT

+62895395793881 | taufikhdyt0106@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/tfkhdyt/ | taufik-portfolio.vercel.app | Tasikmalaya, Indonesia

PROFILE

Undergraduate Information Technology Education Student at the Faculty of Computer Science, Brawijaya University, with a strong interest in education, programming, web development, and related fields. My academic journey has equipped me with a deep understanding of education and computer science. I've successfully theoretical knowledge into practical experience through roles as a practicum assistant. Furthermore, my active involvement in diverse campus organizations has enhanced my skills and expertise, further solidifying my readiness to excel in diverse IT-related roles.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

BRAWIJAYA UNIVERSITY

2021 - Present

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology Education

- Current GPA: 3.78 out of 4.0 (4th Semester)
- Teaching Assistant at DSI FILKOM UB
- Practicum Assistant at FILKOM UB
- IT Development at DIGITAL CREATIVE MASJID RADEN PATAH UB

WORK EXPERIENCE

DIGITAL CREATIVE MASJID RADEN PATAH UB

Sep 2023 – Present

IT Development

- Developed a new website for Masjid Raden Patah UB using the Laravel framework
- Collaborated with team to identify technical needs & integrate new features per design guidelines
- Implemented version control and streamlined collaborative development processes by integrating Git

DEPARTMENT OF INFORMATION SYSTEMS (DSI FILKOM UB)

Sep 2023 – Dec 2023

Teaching Assistant in International Class

- Assisted 2 lecturers in Basic Programming and Computational Mathematics courses
- Translated and revamped teaching materials for international class students
- Supported curriculum development through English translation of course documents
- Provided valuable feedback and corrections for student assignments

FACULTY OF COMPUTER SCIENCE (FILKOM UB)

Aug 2023 – Dec 2023

Practicum Assistant of 4 Courses

- Taught practicum sessions for courses Basic Programming, User Interface Design, Data Structures and Algorithms, and Database Design & SQL
- Taught 40 students about user interface design, 38 students about Java basic programming, 25 students about data structures and algorithms, and 20 students about database design and SQL programming
- Conducted practicum sessions and provided practicum feedback and assessment
- Achieved a 98% success rate of student understanding based on the end-of-practicum assessment

FACULTY OF COMPUTER SCIENCE (FILKOM UB)

Feb 2023 – Jun 2023

Practicum Assistant of Object-Oriented Programming

- Taught 36 students about Java object-oriented programming
- Conducted practicum sessions and provided practicum feedback and assessment
- Achieved a 97% success rate of student understanding based on the end-of-practicum assessment

FACULTY OF COMPUTER SCIENCE (FILKOM UB)

Sep 2022 – Dec 2022

Practicum Assistant of Basic Programming

- Taught 37 students about Java basic programming
- Conducted practicum sessions and provided practicum feedback and assessment
- Achieved a 95% success rate of student understanding based on the end-of-practicum assessment

ORGANIZATIONAL & COMMITTEE EXPERIENCE

POROS ORGANIZATION OF OPEN SOURCE FILKOM UB

Mar 2023 - Present

Staff of Security Division

- Learned how to secure code, implement security as code, and secure systems
- Enhanced security problem-solving skills through participating in Capture the Flag (CTF) challenges and collaborating
 with a team

Feb 2023 - Dec 2023

Secretary

- Managed the administrative needs and maintained the organization's inventory
- Maintained and preserved organizational documents, records, and archives
- Successfully managed the submission of over 100+ work program administration documents, including proposals, accountability reports, final activity reports, letters, etc.

GEMASTIK XVI 2023 Sep 2023

Staff of IT Division

- Managed the technology infrastructure required for event, supporting 850+ participating teams and ensuring smooth operations throughout the event
- Ensured all technology devices' smooth functionality and connectivity, guaranteeing uninterrupted operations.
- Provided technical support to all involved teams, troubleshooting technical issues and delivering real-time solutions.

KBMPTI FILKOM UB 2022/2023

Feb 2022 - Jan 2023

Staff of Organizational Quality Assurance Center

- Fostered and enhanced the quality and quantity of human resources within the organization
- Developed and implemented training and development programs to improve the skills and knowledge of staff members
- Conducted thorough performance monitoring for all 57 members of the organization

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

STUBABY Sep 2023 – Nov 2023

Final Project of Course: Information System Implementation and Testing

- Developed a Stunting Education System targeting postpartum mothers, implemented as a website
- Served as a full-stack developer, leading the development using the Laravel framework
- Collaborated with a team to ensure comprehensive testing, debugging, and deployment of the website
- Documented the development process, including technical aspects and functionalities of the system

PURRFECT ADOPT Mar 2023 – Jun 2023

Final Project of Course: Web Programming and Internet Technology

- Collaborated on a class project to create a cat adoption website using the Laravel framework
- Contributed to both front-end and back-end development, integrating functionalities into a GitHub repository
- Collaborated with team members to design and implement features for the website

E-BLOCK Mar 2023 – Jun 2023

Final Project of Course: Knowledge and Learning Resource Management

- Created a prototype web-based learning resource for Java using block-based coding
- Utilized Figma to design and develop the user interface and layout of the learning resource platform
- Collaborated with team members to conceptualize and execute the prototype's design and functionality

PARTNER IN CODE Feb 2023 – Jun 2023

Final Project of Course: Instructional Media Interaction Design

- Developed a prototype for basic programming instructional media using Figma
- Collaborated within a team consisting of UI Designer, UX Designer, and UX Researcher
- Responsible for the visual design and user interface aspects of the instructional media project

GAME DEV PRENEUR Sep 2022 – Dec 2022

Final Project of Course: User Interface Design

- Developed a static web-based learning platform focused on game development
- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap framework for platform development
- Collaborated with a team to create and implement the platform's user interface design

ADDITIONAL

Soft Skills : Time Management, Problem Solving, Team Building, Team Management, Teamwork, Leadership, High Analytical, Highly Motivated, Adaptability, Critical Thinking, Flexibility, Empathy, Creativity, Networking, Teaching

Technical Skills: Java, Python, C, C++, C#. Net, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Golang, Dart, Kotlin, HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Chakra UI, jQuery, Vite, Laravel, CodeIgniter, Vue.js, React, js, Next.js, Angular, Node.js, Flutter, Git, GitHub, GitLab, MySQL Database, MariaDB, IBM DB2, CMS

Languages: Indonesian (Native) and English